CV OF MR. SELVAM

Permanent address:

Sree Vihar

TC 16 / 681 - 60, 15 F, Heera Heritage Kochar Road, Thycaud PO, Jagathy

Trivandrum 695 014 Mobile No. : 97 45 85 6112

E - mail ID : selvam.shj@gmail.com

Career objective:

As I have more than 25 years of work experience in accounting and auditing, I would like to use my ability and integrity in accounting and auditing field with a view to improve my knowledge and potential skill which will in turn enable the organization to achieve its target and growth.

As far as auditing is concerned, I have vast experience in audit of small, medium and large organizations which includes trading, manufacturing and contracting companies. I have visited all over India for Inspection, Revenue audit and Final audit of nationalized banks. Besides, I have experience in audit of schools and colleges also.

Work experience:

Director:

March 2019 to till date (Present Position)

Supreme Insurance Services & Consultancy, Trivandrum.

Presently I am running this Consultancy firm. The main products I am handling are Bank Credit Facilities, Bank loans, various insurance products, investment advises etc.

Insurance Manager:

March 2018 to February 2019 (1 year)

Pnb MeLlife Insurance Co. Ltd, Pattom, Trivandrum.

Pnb MeLlife Insurance Co. Ltd is one of the leading Life Insurance companies in India. It has been present here 2001. They are functioning over 150 locations across the country and serves customers in more than 7000 locations through its bank partnership with PNB, JKB and KBL. They have morethan 10,000 employees all over India. Their main products are Family protection, Long Term savings, Retirement and Child Education plan. I was involed in boosting our branch's sales.

Accounts & Finance Manager:

May 2016 to February 2018 (1 year 9 months)

Rasana Group of Companies, Sharjah, UAE.

Rasana Group is mainly concentrating in structural steel contracting and engineering business having present Contract Revenue of Aed 100 Million per annum. Rasana and its allied concerns already geared up for its expansion process in all terms in order to achieve its targeted Contracts Revenue per annum for Aed 350M to Aed 400 Million in the coming 4 years.

Duties and responsibilities: Handled all accounts and finance activites which includes,

- ▼ Monitoring movements of all banks on daily basis
- √ Preparing Cash Forecast, Budgets and comparing it with actuals and analysing variances
- ✓ Prearing Cash Flow statement for company operations, bank finance and real estate loan
- ▼ Taking all effort to boost monthly collection
- ✓ Arranging disbursement of fund systematically based on actual cash inflow.
- ✓ Utilization of bank credit facilities with respect to OD, LC, TR, CD, Open account, PPC, LBD, BGs etc and its subsequent settlement.
- ✓ Preparing projected P & L account and Balance Sheet on monthly basis, comparing it with actuals and analysing variances
- V Reporting all accounts and finance movements to the Group CFO on daily, weekly and monthly basis
- ✓ Guiding all accountants for completing their rotuine accounts works as well as for the preparation of books of account of individual companies and its consolidation.
- ▼ Finalization of accounts, preparing inhouse Financial Statements and Financial Analysis.
- ▼ Dealing with internal auditors and external auditors

Accounts Manager:

Rasana Group of Companies, Sharjah, UAE.

September 2014 to April 2016 (1 year 8 months)

Duties and responsibilities: Handled all accounts matters and controlled accounts dept in all sense.

- ✓ Preparing budgets, comparing it with actuals and analysing variances
- ▼ Preparing Projected Cash Flow Statements for project finance and for availing OD agaist CF and PPC.
- Assisting Group CFO in all finance functions including preparation of monthly Projected CFS, comparing it with actual monthly commitments, arranging required fund to meet normal and emergency situations and ensuring smooth inflow and outflow of fund which will enable the company for its smooth operation.
- V Finalization of accounts and preparing In-House Financial Statements and Ratio Analysis.

Chief Accountant:

February 1996 to August 2014 (18 years 7 months)

Rasana Engineeing Ind Co LLC & allied concerns, Sharjah, UAE.

Rasana is pecialized in structural steel and spece frame works. It is a Sharjah based company havings its branches in Dubai and Abu Dhabi. There are 5 companies in Rasana Group having total strength of 250 employees. Moreover, Rasana is outsourcing around 400 plus workers every month to carryout its running projects in various Emirates especially in Sharjah, Dubai and Abu Dhabi.

Duties and responsibilities:

- ✓ Complete checking of all accounts including cash, bank, Accounts Payable, AR, Sales, Collection etc
- √ Supervising the preparation of invoices to the Clients every month
- ✓ Supervising the preperation of Salary and wages every month
- ✓ Supervising the preperation of export LC documents and import LC applications etc
- ✓ Handling LCs, TRs, CDs, LBD, PPC, invoice discounting, BGs with respect to bank credit facilities
- ▼ Preparing all most all correspondence for and on behalf of accounts department
- ✓ Submiting report to Management on Sales, collection, debtors on monthly basis
- ✓ Laise with Clients for the collection of major payments and attending meetings in disputed cases.
- ✓ MIS reporting to Management on monthly basis
- √ Negotiating with banks for availing project finance and preparing Projected Cash Flow Statements
- V Finalization of accounts and providing required assistance to internal and external auditors
- V Preparing In-House FS of all individual companies and its consolidation on frequent intervals
- At the end of every fiscal year, I was used to prepare a detailed 'INTERNAL REPORT' comprising Income statement, Position statement, Cash flow statement, Statement of changes in Equity Ratio analysis, Cost volume profit analysis, Graphic report, Overhead Analysis etc with a view to show company's position internally.

Accounts Officer:

July 1993 to January 1996 (2 years 7 months)

Western Express Pvt Ltd, Khanpur, New Delhi.

Western Express Pvt Ltd is an exporting company having its HO in Madras and branch offices in Delhi and Punjab. They are specialized in preparing quilt products and exporting the same to various European countries

Duties and responsibilities:

- ✓ Controlled accounts and finance department for its Delhi branch
- V Controlled the preperation of books of accounts
- ▼ Finalization of accounts and visiting Head Office every year for assisting final auditors

Auditor:

April 1989 to June 1993 (4 years 3 months)

DP Kapoor & Co, CAs, N 52 Cannaught Place, New Delhi

- ✓ Worked as an auditor for 4 years out of which I have spent 3 years for CA articleship
- V Got lots of audit experience in small, medium and large companies in this period of time.

Page No. 2 of 3

CA articleship:

April 1990 to March 1993 (3 years)

DP Kapoor & Co, CAs, N 52, Cannaught Place, New Delhi

- Completed 3 years CA articleship as per the rules and regulations of The Institute of Chartered Accountants of India.
- Experience in audit of small, medium and large companies including Equipment Conductors and Cables Ltd, Nehru Place, New Delhi, Laxman & Sylvania Ltd Kanpur and Jabalpur branches in UP and MP respectively.
- We were in the audit panel of Punjab National Bank (PNB) and as per the contract with them, we have visited various branches of PNB in north india for the Inspection and Revenue audit.

 Travelled all over India for Final audit of nationalized banks including PNB, SBI, Indian bank, SBT etc.
- V Experience in audit of schools and colleges including Bal Bharati public school Pitampura, New Delhi and MSM College Kayamkulam, Kerala.

Faculty in Commerce:

December 1989 to February 1990 (3 months)

Excellent Pvt College - Kayamkulam, Kerala.

Experience in teaching Degree students for Cost Accounting, Accountancy and Managerial Economics

Education:

Sn Qualificati	ons	Splz	University	Year
1 CFM	Chartered Finance Manager	Fin	ISBM, Mumbai	2013-15
2 DMS	Doctorate in Management Studies	Fin	KSBM, Mumbai	2011-13
3 MBA	Master of Business Administration	Fin	Kazian, Mumbai	2010-12
4 DFM	Diploma in Financial Management	Fin	AIIMS, Chennai	2002
5 M.Com	Master of Commerce	Fin	Kerala University	1987-89
6 B.Com	Bachelor of Commerce	Costing	Kerala University	1984-87

Completed Courses:

1 CPA	10 months review course completed	Emerge MTC, Dubai	2010-11
(2) CA	3 years practical training course completed	ICAL New Delhi	1990-93

Technical skill:

- 1 Executive Level computer course passed from CSIT, New Delhi.
- 2 Working knowledge of Dac easy accounting program
- (3) Working knowledge of Beams ERP Accounting system
- 4 Tally9 ERP system basic knowledge

Certificate of participation:

- 1 Obtained a Certificate of participation on Value Stream Analysis from Four Principles, Dubai
- (2) Obtained a Certificate of participation on Basic Fire Fighting from Eurolink Safety, Dubai, UAE

Language skill:

٧	English	Writing & Reading	•	Excellent
٧	Malayalam	Writing & Reading	•	Excellent
٧	Hindi	Writing & Reading	•	Very Good

▼ Two daughters » Eng Final & BBA Aviation

Others:

٧	Interpersonal •			Very Good
٧	Ability to work as a team			Very Good
٧	Passion •	Accounting & Fir	nance	e work
٧	Hobbies •	Reading, watchin	g TV	news, Chess

Personal datas:

٧	Name	>>	Selvam. V	Religion	»	Hindu
٧	Sex	>>	Male	Nationality	»	Indian
٧	DOB	>>	13.05.1967	Driving	»	Holder of Indian and UAE
٧	Marital status	>>	Married			driving license holder

Declaration:

I hereby declare that the information furnished above are true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Signature	Selvam	Page No. 3 of 3